>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 好的，希望我们对词法范围有很好的感觉。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Okay, so hopefully we're
feeling pretty good about lexical scope.
但让我们测试一下这个存在的一些小边缘和角落案例。
But let's test some of the little edges
and corner cases that exist within this.
让我们确保我们的理解是完全有效的。
Let's make sure our
understanding is fully working.
所以我们要像之前的幻灯片一样处理这件
So, we're gonna process this exactly the
same way as we did on the previous slide,
就是我们要先进行编译，然后执行。
which is that we want to first do the
compilation, and then do the execution.
既然你现在都是我的专家了
Since you're now all experts and
certified in this I'm gonna expect
你就能跟我说这些事了
you to be able to follow along and
say out loud with me all of these things.
因此，处理开始时，编译器将与作用域管理器对话。
So processing begins with the compiler
talking to the scope manager.
编译器在第 1 行，嘿 scope manager.
And compiler says on line one,
hey scope manager.
全球范围，我有一个，什么样的参考?
Hey global scope, I have a,
what kind of reference?
我有一个正式的声明，执行中它是一个目标参考，但是，
I have a formal declaration, in execution
it will be a target reference but,
在我的编译期间我有一个正式的
during my compilation I have a formal
宣言
declaration for
>> 演讲者 2: 教师 >> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 老师。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Teacher
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Teacher.
听说过吗
Ever heard of it?
而答案是
And the answer is
>> 扬声器 2: 是 >> 扬声器 3: 否
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 没有，没有听说过。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: No, haven't heard of it.
这是在编译阶段。
This is in compilation stage.
我们会在行刑时听到它的
We will of heard of it in execution.
在编译阶段，我们从未听说过它。
In compilation stage
we'd never heard of it.
那么我们就去创造什么样的大理石?
So we go ahead and
create what kind of marble?
>> 演讲者 3: 红色。 >> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是你的红色
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your red
大理石好吗
marble, okay?
然后我们把红球，布普直接掉到红桶里。
And we drop the red ball, boop,
directly into the red bucket.
现在，我们在什么方面找到了下一个正式声明 ?
Now we find the next formal
declaration on what line?
>> 扬声器 3: 3。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Three.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 第三行。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Line three.
我们有正式声明
We have the formal declaration.
已调用的标识的全局作用域正式声明。
Hey global scope formal declaration for
an identifier called.
其他类。 OtherClass，听说过吗 ?
OtherClass.
OtherClass, ever heard of it?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
>> 演讲者 3: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
>> Kyle Simpson: 从未听说过。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Never heard of it.
太好了我们需要什么
Great, so we need a what?
>演讲者 3: 红色大理石。 >> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red marble.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Red marble.
这是你的红色大理石 boop 在红桶里
Here's your red marble, boop,
goes in the red bucket.
顺便说下，全球范围，这是一个功能。
By the way, global scope,
that's a function.
它需要自己的桶。
It needs its own bucket.
你能给我做个蓝桶吗
Can you make me a blue bucket?
好的我们做个蓝色的水桶
Sure, we make a blue bucket.
这里是你的蓝色水桶现在我们进入那个范围
Here is your blue bucket and
now we step into that scope and
我们会处理它的计划或者制定计划
we process its plan, or we make it's plan.
那么下一份我们发现的正式声明呢 ?
So where is the next formal
declaration that we find?
>演讲者 2: 第四行。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Line four.
>> 扬声器 3: 9。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Nine.
>> 扬声器 2: 等待分钟。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Wait a minute.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 第四行是否正式声明?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Is line
four a formal declaration?
>> 演讲者 3: 否。 >> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 没有 var 。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: There's no var there.
第五行，那是正式声明吗 ?
What about line five,
is that a formal declaration?
>> 演讲者 3: 否。 >> 凯尔辛普森: 第六行，
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: What about line six,
正式声明吗
formal declaration?
>> 扬声器 2: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: No.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 我们没有蓝色的弹珠吗 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We don't
make any blue marbles, do we?
好的记住这一点
Okay, so keep that in mind.
你可能想知道第五行会发生什么
You may be wondering what's
gonna happen with line five, and
我们会在执行过程中讨论这个问题，但从编译器的角度来看，
we'll talk about that during execution,
but from the perspective of the compiler,
我们没有正式的声明所以没有弹珠来创造
we didn't have any formal declarations,
so there's no marbles to create.
好了我们和蓝桶一起完成了
Okay so we're done with the blue bucket.
实际上，它存在，但实际上它没有弹珠。
Effectively it exists, but
effectively it has no marbles in it.
我们走出去，回到全球范围。
We step back out to the global scope.
我们是否在此计划中找到了正式声明 ?
Do we find anymore formal
declarations in this program?
>> 演讲者 3: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 我们完成了汇编。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So
we're done with compilation.
大拇指，大拇指，我们感觉如何 ?
Thumbs up, thumbs down, how do we feel?
好的，和以前一样的过程。
Okay, same process as before.
我还想训练你把那个故事告诉你
And I'm trying to train you to have
that narrative in your head even if
在这次研讨会之后你永远不会再大声说出来了
you never say the words out loud
ever again after this workshop.
我想让你想想你脑袋里的故事
I want you to think that
narrative in your head.
想想这个问题，回答这个问题，因为会谈是关于
Think about the question and answering
that is happening because that talks about
或说明编译器与作用域计划之间发生的交换。
or illustrates the interchange that occurs
between the compiler and the scope plan.
这就是你如何理解范围工作的方式
That's how you understand how scopes work,
就是当你明白他们是怎么成立的，以及他们是如何使用的，好吗 ?
is when you understand how they get
set up, and how they get used, okay?
现在，让我们执行此代码。
So now, let's execute this code.
它的执行方式与我们在前一张幻灯片中所做的完全一样。
It executes exactly the same way as we
would have, done in the previous slide.
所以我们记得没有正式声明
So we remember,
there's no formal declarations but
有可执行语句。
there are executable statements.
第一个行具有可执行语句。
Line one has an executable statement.
所以我们才是引擎
And so we are the engine and
我们说，哎，全球范围，我有一个什么样的参考?
we say, hey, global scope,
I have a.what kind of reference?
>> 演讲者 3: 目标。 >> Kyle Simpson: 我有一个目标引用
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Target.
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I have a target reference
老师的
for teacher.
听说过吗
Ever heard of it?
答案是: >> 演讲者 2: 是的。
And the answer is,
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
>> Kyle Simpson: Nope. >> 扬声器 2: 是。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Nope.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yeah.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是你的红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your red marble.
对对对。
Yes, right yes.
你是什么颜色的大理石
Here’s your what color marble?
>> 演讲者 3: 红色。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是你的红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here’s your red marble.
太好了我们用凯尔的报价把它分配给红色的大理石
Great, we take the value quote Kyle,
we assign it into the red marble, and
我们已经完成了
we are complete.
每个人都有好处吗
Everybody good with that?
好吧好吧
All right.
记住，函数是声明，它们不存在。
Now remember, functions are declarations,
they don't really exist.
至少他们在这里只是象征性的
At least, they're only here symbolically.
所以我们要从功能转移到下一行代码
So we're going to move from the function
to the next execution line of code,
那是第九行
which would be line nine.
第九行如何执行?
How does line nine execute?
>> 演讲者 3: 全球范围。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Hey global scope.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 全球范围，这就是红桶。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Hey global scope,
that's the red bucket.
全球范围我在这里有什么参考 ?
Hey global scope I have what
kind of reference here?
我9 线有什么参考
What kind of reference
do I have on line nine?
>> 扬声器 2: 源。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Source.
>> Kyle Simpson: 源引用，我有源引用
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Source reference,
I have a source reference for
标识为其他类的标识。
an identifier called other class.
你以前听过他吗
Have you ever heard of him before?
答案是吗 ?
And the answer is?
> 演讲者 2: 是的，这是你的红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes, here's your red marble.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是你的红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your red marble.
谢谢你来接吧
Thanks, you're picking up on it.
好了这是你的红色大理石好吗
Right, here's your red marble, okay?
我知道这听起来很傻
I know it sounds silly.
但它能帮助你处理一个真正干涸的
But it helps you process what would
otherwise be a really dry and
无聊的话题
boring topic.
所以就跟我说吧好吧
So, just stick with me, all right.
这是你的红色大理石
Here's your red marble.
那红色弹珠里有什么
So, what do we find in that red marble?
>> 演讲者 2: 参考。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: A reference.
>> Kyle Simpson: 引用我们已调用的函数
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: A reference to
the function which we've called
此处的 otherClass 在此处附加了此蓝色范围的范围。
otherClass here which has attached
to it this blue bucket of scope.
所以我们找到了这个函数，我们用第 9 行的括号来执行它，
So we find that function, we execute it
with the parenthesis on line nine, and
行刑 ?
execution moves to what line?
>> 扬声器 3: 4。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Four.
>> Kyle Simpson: 第四行，第 4 行如何执行?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Line four,
how does line four execute?
>演讲者 3: 嘿，蓝色的水桶。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Hey, blue bucket.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 嘿，蓝桶，我有一个，什么样的参考?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Hey, blue bucket,
I have a, what kind of reference?
>> 扬声器 3: 源。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Source.
>> Kyle Simpson: 我有目标引用，因为它正在接收分配。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: I have a target reference
because it is receiving an assignment.
我有个老师的目标参考。
I have a target reference for teacher.
听说过，答案是吗 ?
Ever heard of it, and the answer is?
>> 演讲者 3: 否。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: No.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 那么我们去哪里 ?
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So where do we go?
就一个 >> 演讲者 2: 上一个。
One up.
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Up one.
>> Kyle Simpson: 嘿，全球范围，我有一个目标引用
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Hey, global scope,
I have a target reference for
是老师的耳闻
teacher ever heard of it.
>> 扬声器 2: 是。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Yes.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 这是你的
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Here's your.
>演讲者 3: 红色大理石。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 3: Red marble.
>> 凯尔 - 辛普森: 重要的是，这里的红色大理石不是蓝色的大理石。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Important to see that
it's a red marble here not a blue marble.
虽然我们位于蓝色范围内，但我们正在引用红色的大理石。
Even though we're inside of the blue
scope, we are referencing a red marble.
你和我一起吗
You with me?
我们得到一个红色的大理石当我们给它分配报价时
So we get a red marble and
when we assign quote Suzy to it,
我们正在分配目前的价值
we are assigning over the value
that was currently there,
因为这个箱子里的大理石是一样的
the quote Kyle,
because it's the same marble in this case.
这不是因为我们没在大等舱里申报老师
This wasn't shadowed because we didn't
declare teacher inside of the otherClass
函数。
function.